<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tutorial on Edwin's Blog</title><link>https://hyperupcall.github.io/blog/categories/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in tutorial on Edwin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 22:00:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hyperupcall.github.io/blog/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terminal Automation with Expect</title><link>https://hyperupcall.github.io/blog/posts/terminal-automation-with-expect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 22:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://hyperupcall.github.io/blog/posts/terminal-automation-with-expect/</guid><description>Expect is THE tool for automating tasks in the terminal. It is extremely helpful if you need to automate sending input to a program directly on the command line.
This guide is targeted towards developers that wish to automate sending and receiving input from a program, without having to read long manual pages or fragmented StackOverflow answers. I&amp;rsquo;m going to skimp on technical details relating to Expect and the concepts around it; for that, there are plenty of resources online</description></item><item><title>Render LaTeX with KaTex in Hugo Blog</title><link>https://hyperupcall.github.io/blog/posts/render-latex-with-katex-in-hugo-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 11:26:16 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://hyperupcall.github.io/blog/posts/render-latex-with-katex-in-hugo-blog/</guid><description>Just recently, I added support to render LaTeX math equations with the rendering engine KaTeX for this blog. I chose it over MathJax because it performs substantially faster. To integrate KaTeX in my Hugo blog, I used the Mmark Markdown processor rather than Hugo's default Blackfriday processor.
There are three steps to follow so you can write LaTeX in markdown for KaTeX to use.
Create a KateX partial Integrate the KateX partial in your header or footer element Activate the KaTeX partial in the markdown file What is a partial?</description></item></channel></rss>