<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>math on Edwin's Blog</title><link>https://eankeen.github.io/blog/categories/math/</link><description>Recent content in math on Edwin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:41:42 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eankeen.github.io/blog/categories/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fibonacci Equation for Zth (Nth) Term Using Pascal's Triangle (Part 2 of 2)</title><link>https://eankeen.github.io/blog/posts/fibonacci-equation-using-pascals-triangle-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:41:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://eankeen.github.io/blog/posts/fibonacci-equation-using-pascals-triangle-part-2/</guid><description>If you're not familiar with Pascal's Triangle, see part 1.
Finding a Formula How do we leverage the relationship (in the image above) to obtain an equation that obtains the \(z\)th term (\(Fib(z)\), or \(F(z)\)) in the Fibonacci sequence? First, we need to figure out what our equation may look like. We know we're adding up terms of the Fibonacci sequence, so a summation symbol will be used. Additionally, we are adding up terms from Pascal's triangle, where each term individually can be written as \(_nC_r\).</description></item><item><title>Fibonacci Equation for Zth (Nth) Term Using Pascal's Triangle (Part 1 of 2)</title><link>https://eankeen.github.io/blog/posts/fibonacci-equation-using-pascals-triangle-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 10:10:57 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://eankeen.github.io/blog/posts/fibonacci-equation-using-pascals-triangle-part-1/</guid><description>If you're familiar with the intricacies of Pascal's Triangle, see how I did it by going to part 2.
Background of Pascal's Triangle A while back, I was reintroduced to Pascal's Triangle by my pre-calculus teacher. Pascal's triangle can be written as an infintely expanding triangle, with each term being generated as the sum of the two numbers adjacently above it. For example, both \(10\)s in the triangle below are the sum of \(6\) and \(4\).</description></item></channel></rss>